本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：桃乐 马蒂 米苏 草草 暮羽 蝉衣 圆圆 断电
时间轴：小怡子 潘叔
■
校对：饿得慌  地瓜
后期&总监：丢丢
■
诉 讼 双 雄
第一季 第五集
你的
Voila.
巨无霸
Triple double,
来自于美国最大的快餐连锁
courtesy of America's favorite burger chain.
路易赢了那起集体诉讼案吗
Louis won the class-action suit?
? 一万名哈佛人  今日渴望胜利 ?
? 10,000 men of Harvard want victory today ?
此为哈佛战歌之一  名为《一万名哈佛人》
? 他们深知与耶鲁人对抗 ?
? For they know that o'er old Eli ?
? 哈佛稳操胜券 ?
? Fair Harvard holds sway ?
? 耶鲁人终将败在我们手下 ?
? So we'll conquer all old Eli's men ?
我最喜欢这段
My favorite part.
你根本不知道歌词  对吧
You don't know the lyrics, do you?
我也不记得  路易
I don't even know the lyrics, Louis.
我们这里是律师事务所
Now are we practicing law down here,
还是合唱队的排练房
or auditioning a chorus line?
这叫作团队精神
It's called esprit de corps.
法官撤销了我那个陪审团判的一百万赔偿裁决
And I just got a $100 million jury award overturned.
我从来不用撤销什么裁决
I don't have to overturn awards like that
因为我从一开始就不会输
because I've never lost one in the first place.
这是什么味道  你的新香水味
So what is this, a new cologne
还是嫉妒的气息
or just a hint of jealousy?
我很惊讶  你...
I'm surprised you, uh,
没闻出来这是你老婆用的香水
don't recognize your wife's perfume.
我知道你没结婚
I know, you're not married.
但这话还是很搞笑
It's still funny.
你应该知道我们是在
You do realize we're celebrating
为让富人更富这种事庆祝吧
making fat people even fatter, right?
你要是想做好事
If you wanted to do good,
就该去当个冒牌医生
you should've been a fake doctor.
你的名片
Business cards.
皮尔逊・哈德曼律所
迈克・罗斯
律师助理
谢了
Yup.
我这是将错就错  跟我来
My mistake is now official. Come with me.
还有  赶紧把那首哈佛的破战歌给学会
and learn the goddamn lyrics to the Harvard song, will ya?
奥克斯克投资公司已经同意签署
Oakhurst capital has agreed
这份两亿美元的授权合约
to a $200 million licensing deal.
我们快要拿下了
We are at the goal line.
品牌保护方面做得怎样
How are we on brand protection?
合同可谓无懈可击
The contract is airtight.
现在唯一的问题就是
The only issue here
怎样让巧艺福玩具公司签约
is to get the Joyful Toy Company to close.
我会亲自和乔伊谈
I'll go over it with Joy one-on-one.
基本的会议礼仪就是把手机调成静音
Protocol in a meeting is to put your phone on silent.
既然响了
And if it does ring,
你就接
You answer it.
出去接
Not in here.
打完电话不用急着回来了
Don't feel the need to rush back when you're done.
请问哪位
Who is this?
是我  特雷弗  先别挂
Dude, it's Trevor. Don't hang up.
我只能打一个电话
I only get one call.
我被抓了
I'm in jail.
我想从港务局坐长途车
I--I tried to hop this bus at port authority.
但我喝醉了  闹得一塌糊涂
I was drunk. It's all messed up.
我知道上次打架之后  我们再没说过话
Look, I know we haven't talked since we fought,
但我不知道还能打给谁
but I didn't know who else to call.
抱歉  真的对不起
I'm sorry, man. I'm sorry.
没事
Okay.
-钱我会还你的  -那最好
- I'm gonna pay you back.  - Good.
为了保释你出来  我把存款都花光了
Your bail cost me everything I have in the bank.
问题是
The thing is,
我现在没钱了
I don't have the money.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你卖大麻一个月能净赚一万
You're clearing $10,000 a month selling weed.
我以前赚得快  花得也快
It went out as fast as it came in.
以前
Came in?
我洗手不干了
I quit. I'm not dealing anymore.
-屁话  -我是说真的
- Bullshit.  - I'm serious.
我们打完架之后  不知道为什么
After we fought, I don't know.
我的生活就分崩离析了
Things just started to fall apart.
珍妮和我分手了
Jenny broke up with me.
没人告诉我
I didn't know.
这让我意识到  该改变自己了
Well, I just realized I needed to make a change.
我把水烟枪都给卖了
Even sold my bong.
你和以前不一样了
What have you done with my friend?
你还说我呢
Yeah. You should talk.
看看你  简直就是高登・盖哥的翻版
Look at you. You look like Gordon Gekko's little brother.
美国演员  扮演《华尔街》中的投机家
得了吧
Okay.
怎么样  在华尔街工作吗
What, are you working on Wall Street, man?
为什么要给我打电话
Why'd you call me, Trevor?
因为我知道只有你会管我
You're the one person I knew would show up.
你还想要我帮别的忙吗
You want to ask me for anything..else?
我现在唯一要做的
Look, all I care about right now
就是洗清我的案底
is keeping my record clean.
你认不认识好的律师
You don't happen to know any good lawyers, do ya?
不认识
No. I don't.
现在急个什么劲儿
Why the rush now?
你已经浪费了我十分钟的年华
You've already wasted ten minutes of my life.
别告诉我你等了十分钟
Please tell me you didn't wait ten minutes
就为了骂我一顿
just to scold me.
我一直等你把文件拿来
I've been waiting for you to bring the paperwork down
好让我敲定一桩九位数的交易
so I can close a nine-figure licensing deal.
我和雷聊天的时候  你的手机要是再响
If your phone rings while I'm talking to Ray,
我会连你带手机一起扔下车
I'm throwing it out of the car while it's attached to your hand.
埃迪・霍普和男子汉唱的
Eddie Hope and the Mannish Boys.
50年代男歌手以及一个蓝调组合
1959年的  给你三次机会
1959, three guesse.
这还用猜
Guesses?
你低估我了  哈维
You insult me, Harvey.
放心  我们不会迟到
Don't worry, we won't be late.
轮到我了
Okay,
那个唱片公司叫什么名字
what was the name of the record label?
马林唱片
Marlin records.
60年代谁最红
Who covered it in the late '60s?
我想说是滚石  不过...
Ahh! I want to say the stones, but--
要再给你次机会吗
You need some guesses?
就知道是个私人司机
Just like a private car service, huh?
不知道让一让吗
Thinking you don't have to yield?
要我让  是你闯了红灯
What? Yield? You ran a red light!
那是黄灯
That light was yellow!
看清楚先生  是红灯
No, sir, it was not!
你想说我是个骗子咯
Are you calling me a liar?
-离远点  -管好你自己的事  行吗
- Back off. - Mind your business, okay?
这就是我的事
No, I'm minding my business.
谁要是敢动手
Anyone throws a punch,
我就让他尝尝泰瑟枪的威力
Or I'm gonna introduce you to Mr. Taser.
交换保险信息
Trade insurance,
我来一个个记录
I'll take reports, one at a time.
虽然我很想配合你
Yeah, as much as I'd like to help you out,
但我有个面谈要迟到了
I'm late for a meeting.
你哪都别想去  我得给你们俩录口供
You're not going anywhere. I need a statement from you too.
这是我的信息
Here's my information.
我到之前  你先稳住客户
I need you to babysit the client till I get there.
不要提合约的事
And don't mention the deal.
她要是问什么问题
If she asks any questions,
点点头就行
just nod your head
表情迷人一点
and look pretty.
迈克菲女士  我是迈克・罗斯
Ms. Mcafee, I'm Mike Ross.
哈维的同事
I work with Harvey.
你就是那个他不停盛赞的跟班
Oh, you're the protege that he's been gushing about.
他盛赞过我吗
He was gushing?
他提过有你这个人
Well, he mentioned that you existed.
对哈维来说  那就算是盛赞
For Harvey, that's gushing.
他今天要晚点过来
Uh, he's running a few minutes late today.
路上碰了点麻烦
Um, car trouble.
我正要和我的女儿们喝茶
I was just about to have tea with the girls.
一起来喝吗
Would you care to join me?
乐意之极
I'd love to.
好的
Good.
不用那么客气  叫我乔伊就行
And for heaven's sakes, call me Joy.
好的  乔伊
Okay, Joy.
这些...
These...
就是我的女儿们
Are the girls.
苏西  莎拉
Susie, Sarah,
史黛西  辛克莱
Stacy, Sinclair,
还有莎柏琳娜
And Sabrina.
苏西  怎么这么没礼貌
Susie, where are your manners?
快跟这位小伙子握个手
Shake hands with this nice young man.
我说笑呢  我知道这些都是洋娃娃
Just kidding, I know they're dolls.
她们是以我女儿们的名字命名的
They're named after my daughters.
我就是为了她们开的这家公司
I started the company because of them, really.
你要知道  以前的洋娃娃
You know, dolls didn't used to be
可不像现在那些中国制造的劣质塑料玩具
these cheap, plastic bimbos from China that we have today.
而是妈妈一针一线亲手为孩子缝制的
Your mother made them for you by hand.
我也想让我的女儿们玩我亲手缝制的娃娃
I wanted my girls to have that same experience.
可是现在呢  30年之后
And here we are, 30 years later.
这成了每个家长的噩梦
Every parent's worst nightmare.
什么意思
What do you mean?
这些小天使们  每个可以卖到90元
These little angels, they sell for $90 a pop.
我雇管家的钱就是这么赚来的
I wasn't born with a butler, you know.
我不得不说  你很厉害
I gotta say, this is amazing,
竟会愿意把品牌授权给别人
taking on a project like a licensing deal.
有什么厉害的
Why is that amazing?
我奶奶可做不到
Well, my grandmother could never pull this off.
她已经退休十年了
She's been retired for ten years.
那她现在过得怎么样
How is that treating her?
她住得离我家很近
She lives near my apartment.
我每周都去看她一次
I get to see her once a week, so...
-你很孝顺  -不
- That's very sweet of you. - No.
这不是孝顺
No, it's not.
以前  每当我需要她
You know, whenever I needed her,
她都会在一旁支持我
she was there.
无论发生什么
You know, no matter what.
她都会给我个拥抱
She'd give me a hug,
告诉我一切都会没事的
She'd tell me everything is gonna be all right.
即使情况很糟
Even if it wasn't.
现在是她需要我的时候了
And now that she needs me,
但我总是在工作
I am always at work.
我...
And I'm--
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
什么事
Yeah?
永远别在客户面前接电话
Never answer your phone in front of a client.
但是你的电话啊
But it's you.
进展如何
What's happening?
我们正喝茶谈心呢
Well, actually we're in the middle of a tea party.
我就是知道你爱玩洋娃娃
I knew you were the doll-playing type.
让乔伊听电话
Put joy on.
迈克菲女士
Ms. Mcafee.
哈维找您
It's harvey.
乔伊  我很抱歉
Joy, I'm sorry,
咱们得重约了
I have to reschedule.
不用道歉
No need to apologize.
我喜欢眼前这位
I like this one.
喝完茶我就让他回去
I'll send him back after tea.
你不会当着客户的面讨打包盒吧
Tell me you didn't ask our client for a doggy bag.
不能怪我  史黛西坚持要我带给你的
What can I say? Stacy insisted.
刚从乔伊・迈克菲的律师顾问那里回来
Just got off with Joy Mcafee's general counsel.
看样子她已经看透红尘了
It seems she had an epiphany.
她的开价不仅没有提高  反而降低了
She wants less on her plate, not more.
我还以为你能搞定她
I thought you were going to close her.
这个案子我们一定要拿下来
We need that doll money.
我现在就想办法
I'm on top of it.
哈维花了五个月的时间  草拟了这个合约
Harvey took five months to structure that deal.
别把我逼急了
Please don't make me set fire to your desk.
就让你和洋娃娃喝杯茶都做不好
All you had to do was have tea with the dolls.
唐娜  再安排一次和乔伊的茶会
Donna, schedule another tea party with Joy
越快越好
as soon as possible.
然后把她女儿的名字都发给我
And text me the names of her girls.
真的假的啊
Oh, what a shock.
你居然连女孩的名字都记不住
You can't keep girls' names straight in your head.
就记不住你的  黛比
Just yours, Debbie.
看  很搞笑吧  因为你其实叫唐娜
See, that's funny because your name is Donna.
哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
这是你点的东西
I got your order right here.
我没点披萨啊
I didn't order a pizza.
请查收
You've been served.
那个撞了雷的司机
Cab driver who hit Ray
提起了民事诉讼  把我列为目击证人
named me as a witness in a civil suit.
我得去拜访下特雷斯・比克
I need to pay Travis Bickle a visit.
电影《出租车司机》男主角
哈维  如果你能让我和乔伊谈谈
Harvey, if you let me go talk to Joy,
-我肯定能挽回局面  -不必了
- I know I can fix this-- -No.
没人会让一只狗狗清理自己的便便
You don't send a puppy to clean up its own mess.
幸运的是  你没有狗狗需要你担心
Optimally, you don't even have a puppy.
罗斯  据说你和客户聊了下天
Ross, rumor has it you talked a client
就损失了两百万
out of $200 million.
价格还没最终敲定
The deal's not off the table, all right?
只是碰了个钉子
It's just a speed bump.
哥们  我想他又有新绰号了
Dude, I think we just found him a new nickname.
小钉子
Speed bump!
感觉又回到了高中
I feel like I'm back in high school.
你高中的绰号叫小钉子吗
They called you speed bump in high school?
开玩笑啦
Kidding.
但如果你需要个盒子来收拾东西走人的话
But if you need any boxes to pack up your office, just--
等等
Wait a minute, uh--
给
There.
这是你的吧
I think that belongs to you.
如果你皮够厚的话  这些都不算什么
It wouldn't hurt so much if you had thicker skin.
特雷弗来电
什么事
What do you want?
我想还你的保释金
I wanna pay you back for posting bail.
特雷弗  你五年级欠我的40块还没还
Trevor, you've owed me 40 bucks since fifth grade.
一笔勾销了  明白吗
I wrote it off, okay?
听着  我只想洗清案底
Look, I want a clean slate, okay?
如果你不想见我  我会把支票寄给你
So you don't want to see me, I'll mail you a check.
好
Okay.
那明晚见面吧
Yeah, let's hang out tomorrow night.
别玩得太疯  行吗
Nothing crazy, though, all right?
我早上还得早起
I have to be up early.
要想安分一点的话
We can crochet panty hose
我们可以一起织连裤袜
if that's what it takes to be cool.
那也太安分了吧
I think we can do a little better than that.
不如我们...
Why don't we, uh...
7:30在雷克斯酒吧碰头怎么样
Why don't we say Rex's, 7:30.
前六轮我请
First six rounds are on me.
要是你真的想报答我
If you're serious about paying me back,
前一百轮都得你请
the first 100 rounds are on you.
来了个难缠的家伙
So it's the tough guy.
这个问题保险公司就能解决
This is a matter for insurance,
根本不用打官司
not a frivolous lawsuit.
我告诉你
You know, for your information,
我可是遭受了情感创伤
I suffered emotional pain.
情感创伤吗
Emotional pain?
把这些涂在你的伤口上吧
Rub this on your emotional pain.
你这个居高临下的混蛋
You condescending son of a--
看着我  我只提醒你这一次
Look at me, I am gonna warn you once.
别再纠缠了
Do not pursue this matter.
要知道我曾三次从枪口下死里逃生
You know, I have been held up at gunpoint three times.
你认为凭一套名贵的西装
So do you think a fancy suit
和五百元的做发型就能吓唬住我吗
and a $500 haircut, that's gonna scare me?
你要是把我的司机告上法庭
You take my driver to court,
我会亲自为他辩护
I'm gonna represent him myself.
你输了之后
And when you lose,
还要支付我的代理费
you'll be covering my fee,
那可比理个发贵多了
which is gonna be a hell of a lot of haircuts.
原来他不是你临时雇的
Hmm, so you weren't a one-way fare.
雷为我工作了八年
Ray's worked for me eight years.
那你就当不成目击证人了
Then you don't have to worry about being a witness,
因为作为雇主
because as his employer,
你要为他的行为负责
you're liable for his actions.
知道吗  我觉得你是《甜心俏佳人》看多了
You know, I think you've seen way too many reruns of Ally Mcbeal.
美国曾经的热门法律肥皂喜剧
911之后不久  我来到美国
You know, I emigrated here after September 11th,
政府却不允许任何人移民
and they shut the doors on everybody.
我请不起律师  只好亲自将他们告上法庭
I couldn't pay for a lawyer, so I had to take them to court.
我为我的公民权而起诉
I sued for my citizenship,
因此我对法律有着特别的感激之情
so I have a very special appreciation for the law.
我对纯麦威士忌也有感情
I appreciate a good single malt.
但我不会假装自己会酿酒
I don't pretend I can make one.
我让美国政府输得一败涂地  律师
I wiped the floor with the U.S. Government, counselor.
你会受到相同的待遇
I'm gonna do the same with you.
-雷  -唐娜
- Ray.  - Donna.
你来这里做什么  你没找我预约
What are you doin' here? I don't have you scheduled.
我要见哈维
Uh, I need to see Harvey.
你知道规矩的
Oh, come on. You know the rules.
没有搜查证  教皇敕令或是我的许可
No one sets foot in there without a warrant,
谁也别想进去
a papal edict, or my say-so.
我受到了赔偿百万美金的起诉
I just got named in a multimillion-dollar lawsuit.
那场事故不是我的错
The accident wasn't my fault.
我可以去见哈维吗
Can I get in to see Harvey, please?
什么也别说了  我会让你进去的
Okay, say no more. I will get you in.
你有御姐范儿的时候真美
You are so beautiful when you're forceful.
我知道你是在赞美我
I know you meant that as a compliment,
但是我不希望别人夸我美的时候
but I don't appreciate limitations being placed
还加限定词
on my beauty.
哈维  修车就已经花了我很多钱了
Harvey, I'm already losing money with my car in the shop.
参加审讯意味着我还没法工作
A trial means I can't work.
你觉得我的名字
And how do you think my name
会给纽约陪审团留下什么印象
is gonna play in front of a New York jury?
拉希姆・班加西
Rahim Benghazi.
我看来是要买张去关塔那摩的单程票了
I may as well buy a one-way ticket to Guantanamo.
关塔那摩监狱:美军的拘留营  其中的囚犯被怀疑与基地组织有关联
绝对不会
Not gonna happen.
要是我输了
If I lose,
我连办车辆许可证的钱都付不起
I won't even be able to afford a livery license,
更不用谈保险了
let alone my insurance.
所以我要为我们两个辩护
That's why I'm gonna be defending both of us.
雷  这个诉讼处处针对我
Ray, this goes against every fiber of my being.
我来代理你的案子  分文不取
I'm taking your case pro bono.
我不知道要说什么
I don't know what to say.
什么都别说  我得维护我的名誉
Absolutely nothing, I've got a reputation to maintain.
再说  这很快就结束了
Besides, it's not gonna take long, okay?
我不会让法庭受理的
I'm gonna get it dismissed.
唐娜  打给法庭
Donna, call the court.
让他们把这个案子提到前面审理
We need priority status on the docket.
我已经试过了
Yeah, I already tried.
你碰到的是巴勒莫法官
You drew judge Palermo.
你知道你该做什么吧
You know what you have to do, don't you?
知道  又是一个处处针对我的人
Yeah. The other thing that goes against every fiber of my being.
路易  有没有人称赞你是个优雅的男高音
Louis, has anyone told you you're an exquisite soprano?
你想要什么  哈维
What do you want, Harvey?
问得好  让我说违心话太痛苦了
You're right. Why prolong my suffering?
我要你帮我安排和巴勒莫法官见面
I need you to get me in to see judge Palermo.
你要我帮忙  不打算给我点好处吗
You need my help, and you're not gonna pull rank on me?
你这案件和事务所没任何关系  对吧
Your case has nothing to do with firm business, does it?
你要什么
What's it gonna take?
脚部护理还是塞琳时装发布会的票
A mani-pedi? Tickets to Celine?
我帮你去问问
I'll see what I can do.
那你的无理要求是
And your pound of flesh?
我需要人挠背的时候会叫你的
I need my back scratched, I'll let you know.
路易  除非那是什么隐喻  否则免谈
Louis, unless that's a metaphor, the deal's off.
乔伊  我那天告诉你我奶奶活不长了的时候
Joy, when I told you that my grandmother didn't have much time,
我不知道她其实只比你大15岁
I--I didn't realize that she's 15 years older than you.
你怎么知道我多大了
Now, how would you know how old I am?
那可是高度机密啊
That is a very closely guarded secret.
我做了些调查
I did some research.
很机灵嘛
Very resourceful.
我只是为了确定
I did it to assure myself
你能否承受更大的工作量
that you can handle a heavier workload.
多谢关心  但是我不是担心自己的健康
I appreciate that, but I'm not worried about my health.
是因为钱吗
Is it the money?
我可以保证  签约之后  预付的这两亿
Because I can guarantee, 200 million up front
只不过是你将赚到的十分之一
is just 1/10 of what you stand to make on this deal.
迈克
Michael,
我的洋娃娃比大部分人吃得都好
My dolls eat better than most people.
我不缺钱
I've got plenty of money.
而签下这合约  我就要再干五年
This deal meant staying on for five more years
而且工作量要翻一番
and doubling my workload.
我准备带孙子孙女们坐游轮
I am going to take my grandchildren on a cruise
-去塔希提岛玩  -塔希提岛
- to Tahiti.  - Tahiti?
这个授权合约里
You know, the licensing agreement
还包含了一个主题公园
includes a theme park.
你可以带他们去那儿玩啊
You could-- you could take them there.
这跟合约无关
It's not about the deal.
我守着窗外同样的景色过了25年
I have had this same view for 25 years.
我要换个地方
I need a change of scenery.
我会去找哈维  然后跟他说
I am gonna speak to Harvey, and I'm gonna tell him
我要把整个公司都卖掉
that I want to sell the whole business.
那个...
So...
我刚跟巴勒莫法官说好
I just spoke to Judge Palermo.
因为他觉得我是个好人
And because he thinks I'm a good guy,
我还说算我欠他个人情
and I told him I'd owe him one,
所以你的案子被一路向前挪了
your case is gonna be moved up way ahead.
给我挠背吧
Back scratch.
我是家里的独子  不用干那种事
I don't have a firstborn, you know,
你到底想要我怎么报答你
so what exactly do you want for that?
不行  我哪条领带都不能给你
No, you're not getting one of my ties.
不对
No.
你的肩膀怎么了  什么
Your shoulder? What--
你的翻领吗
Your lapel--
你要唐娜吗
Donna?
天啊
Oh, god.
诺玛要去伊斯但布尔待两周
Norma is going to Istanbul for two weeks,
你也知道我跟临时助理处不好
and you know that I'm not good with temps.
我的天啊  你要点别的吧
Oh, my god. Ask me for something else.
哈维  这没的商量
Harvey, this is non-negotiable.
你现在欠我人情呢
You owe me now.
我可不能把唐娜给你
Donna is one thing that I can't give you.
-为什么不能  -首先
- Why not? - For one thing,
她肯定不会同意的
she'd never agree to it.
你是她的老板
You're her boss.
你给她下命令就是了
You just tell her to do stuff.
我从不给她下命令
I don't tell her to do anything.
她很自觉的
She just does.
好啊  这样的话
All right, fine. You know what?
这...  没关系
That's just... Not a problem.
我就给巴勒莫法官打个电话
I will call Judge Palermo,
跟他说我搞错了
and I'll tell him i was mistaken,
你的庭审会被排在
and then your hearing will be in,
大约六个月之后吧
I don't know, maybe six months?
这样吧
I tell you what.
要是你自己能去说服她
If you can convince her yourself,
我就没意见
you have my blessing.
她会爱我爱得欲罢不能
She's gonna love me so much,
你拼了老命才能把她要回来
you're gonna fight to get her back.
你好啊  唐娜
Hi, Donna.
哈维和我刚刚还谈到你呢
Harvey and I were just, uh, talking about you.
不行
No.
你都不知道我要说什么呢
You don't even know what I was gonna say.
我知道
Yes, I do.
怎么可能
And how is that possible?
我读得懂唇语  看得懂肢体语言
I read lips, I know body language,
而且我常跟诺玛聊天
and I talk to Norma.
我不是你游乐园赢来的奖品  路易
I'm not some token you win at a fair, Louis.
我知道你不是  你当然不是奖品
You're not--I know you're not. You're not a token.
我也是个人  而且...
I'm a human being, and I--
是啊  当然
Yes, you are.
对不起  我只是
I'm sorry, I just--
你知道吗  你说的话让我感觉很...
You know what, that just made me feel really...
卑贱
cheap.
我只是想告诉你
I'm just trying to tell you that
你的工作非常出色  唐娜
you're really good at what you do,  Donna.
所以我想请你...
So I'm gonna ask you--
我现在感觉灵魂都受伤了
It's like my soul hurts now.
不  唐娜  听我说
No, Donna, listen,
就算你的灵魂受了点伤...
even if your soul hurts a little bit--
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
不会有事的  别哭啊
It's gonna be fine. Don't cry.
求你别哭啊  唐娜
Please don't cry, Donna.
该死
Oh, shit.
看来我要谢谢你了  演戏太好玩了
I think I owe you one for that. That was fun.
等等  上次你痛哭流涕
Wait a second, the-- the time that you cried,
我就答应让你父母住在我公寓里  那是演的吗
and then I let your parents stay in my condo--
没错
Yup.
你不想说说发生了什么吗
So you don't want to talk about it?
有什么好说的
What is there to talk about?
我做了老板叮嘱我别去做的事
I did exactly what my boss told me not to do,
还把事情都搞砸了
and it blew up in my face.
哥们  我都说我来请客了
Dude, I told you, I'm taking care of this.
在我失业前  就让我最后付一次吧
In my last few hours of employment, please, I should pay.
把钱包收起来
All right, put the wallet away.
皮尔逊・哈德曼律所
迈克・罗斯
律师助理
不赖啊
This is epic.
这东西正适合用来忽悠人
This is the scam we always talked about.
天啊  我敢说你是左右逢"女人缘"呢
God, I bet you're gettin' laid left and right.
对啊  就是这样的
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
过一段时间就没那么好使了
You lose appreciation after a while.
-拿来  -不错
- Come on. - Yeah.
怎么还写上了电话
Why'd you put a phone number on there?
那是家真实存在的公司
It's a real firm.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
打给职员名录处
Oh, I'm just calling the employee directory.
这都是用来忽悠人的
It's part of the scam, man.
-他们会核实你的说法  -别闹了
- They'll check your story. - Stop it.
-怎么  -特雷弗  挂了
- What? - Trevor, stop.
-挂掉电话  -不要
- Hang up the phone. - Oh, no.
特雷弗  挂掉电话
Trevor, hang up the phone, stop!
-怎么了  -好吧  我在那里上班
- What? - All right? I'm working there.
是吗  当上律师了吗
Oh, yeah. What, as a lawyer?
你真的...
Are you--
哥们
Dude.
说来话长  行了吧
It's a long story, okay?
你不能跟任何人说  永远不能  好吗
But you can't tell anyone. Ever. Okay?
太赞了
That is awesome!
我一直都说
Man, I-- I always said
你要是戒了大麻
that if you quit smoking pot,
就能当上律师
you could do it.
是啊
Yeah.
没错  你是说了
Yeah, oh, that's right. Yeah, you did.
就在你把大麻递给我之前
Right before you passed me the bowl.
怎么了
What?
没什么  我就是...
Naw, I just--
希望你能放心地告诉我
I wish you trusted me enough to tell me.
我不就是害你陷进了缉毒突击检查吗
I mean, all I did was set you up on a drug bust.
天呐  现在还不能开这个玩笑是吧
Oh, god, that was too soon.
对不起
I'm sorry.
女士们  你们好啊
Hi, ladies. How are you?
我跟你们说  如果你们任何一个人
Um, I want to let you know, if you--either of you
因为任何事被逮捕了
ever get arrested for anything,
可以给这家伙打电话  他是本市最好的律师
you call this guy. He's the best attorney in the city.
我们为什么会被逮捕呢
Well, what would we get arrested for?
这个嘛  我不知道
Um... I don't know.
你们打算干点什么呢
What are you thinking about doing?
作为你的律师  我绝对要建议你那么干
I-- As your attorney, I would definitely advise you to do that.
-再来四杯  -好的
- Uh, four more. - Yeah.
我必须提醒你  为你自己辩护可不是...
I must warn you that representing yourself at trial is not the--
他怎么在这里
What's he doing here?
你以为你约了和法官见面  我会不知道吗
You think you can schedule a meeting without me knowing it?
不  不
Oh, no.
我有权参与你和法院之间所有的交流
I'm privy to all communication between you and the court.
如果你开车的经验和法律知识一样丰富
Well, if your driving matched your legal knowledge,
我们就不用过来了
we wouldn't be here.
法官大人你好
Your honor.
这个案子不应被受理  这是保险的范畴
This case should be dismissed. It's a matter for insurance.
保险只包括修理费用
Insurance only covers repairs.
却不能弥补我的损失
It does not deal with my losses.
什么损失
What losses?
就因为这场事故
Because of the accident,
我错失了得到出租车执照的机会
I missed my chance to get my taxi medallion.
你就不能明年再买吗
You can't just buy it next year?
我的贷款一周内就要到期了
The loan I got expires in one week.
而且  这次的执照只要三十万
On top of that, a medallion costs 300,000 this go-round.
明年就要三十五万了
Next year, 350.
所以他的所有要求都建立在
So his entire claim rests upon
假设他能获得今年的执照的基础之上
the assumption that he would've won this year's medallion.
美国的特点就是
The hallmark of America
小人物也能得到正义
is that the little guy gets to see justice done.
法律面前人人平等
We are all equals in the eyes of the law.
所以在世界上这么多国家里
That is why, out of all the countries in the world,
我选择来到这里
I chose to come here.
你想怎么回应这个观点呢  律师
What do you got to say about that, counselor?
我得说这位大律师的发言很精彩
I say Atticus Finch makes a good speech here.
安迪克斯・芬奇:小说人物  律师
但这只是一场小事故
But this is a fender-bender,
根本用不着打官司
Not a multimillion-dollar lawsuit.
替代责任适用于
Vicarious liability applies to
歧视  骚扰和意外事故
discrimination, harassment, and accidents.
雇主对雇员的过失负有责任
Employers are responsible for their employees' negligence.
法院觉得这是个合理的诉讼
Court finds a reasonable suit here.
审判明天开始
Trial starts tomorrow.
谢谢你  法官大人
Thank you, your honor.
看我们斗嘴很开心是吧
You're getting a good kick out of this, aren't you?
确实
I am.
但我不是因为这点才接的这案子
But I'm taking this on its merits.
你明天最好拿出你的最高水平
And you better bring your "A" game tomorrow,
因为他提出的是合法要求
'cause he's got a legitimate claim.
他不是想打官司吗
He wants a trial?
看我怎么把他打得落花流水
I'll give him a goddamn trial.
法官大人
Your honor.
你赢过多少个案子了
So how many cases have you won?
我只记得我输了多少场
I only remember how many I've lost.
没输过
None.
等等  怎么还不上酒
Wait, what happened to the drinks?
我有个好主意
I got a better idea.
我们拿一整瓶
Let's say we get a bottle
回你家继续喝如何
and take the party back to your place?
必须得是法国廊酒
Make it a bottle of dom, and you're on.
没问题  四瓶怎么样
All right, how about four bottles?
来吧
Come on.
我们要不要叫个出租车
You guys want to get a cab?
绝对要
Definitely.
绝对要  出租车  四瓶廊酒
Definitely. Cab, four bottles of dom.
你还想再多花点我的钱吗
You want to spend any more of my money?
淡定点  行吗
Just relax, okay?
这叫午夜场消费
It's an investment in the evening.
而且  我之所以说要回家喝
And, uh, I just said the thing about the bottles
就是为了把姑娘们带出酒吧
to get the girls out of the bar.
真的吗  我怎么觉得
Really? 'cause it looked like
你是想躲开那些家伙
you were trying to get away from those guys.
出租车
Taxi!
-什么家伙  -后面那些家伙
- What guys? - The guys in the back.
你知道我指的是谁  快说  那些人是谁
You know what I'm talking about. Come on, who are they?
什么  那两个吗  我不知道
What? Those two? I--I--I don't know.
出租车都去哪了
Where are all the...cabs?
看样子他们可认识你
Well, it looked like they knew you,
而且不是因为什么好事
and not in a very good way.
我不知道  也许他们刚才
I--I don't know. Maybe they were, uh,
跟我们的姑娘调情来着  好吧
flirting with our dates, okay?
要是我看到那两个美腿姑娘离我而去
I'd be pissed too if I watched those legs
我也会很生气的
walk away from me.
感觉怎样  姑娘们
How are we doin', ladies?
穿这双高跟鞋  我的脚要疼死了
My feet are killing me in these heels.
-不好意思   -特雷弗  别闹了
- I'm sorry. - Hey, Trevor, come on--
出租车
Taxi!
说真的  别跟我闹了  刚才到底怎么回事
Seriously, stop playing with me. What was that about back there?
我没跟你闹  好吧
Look, I'm not playing with you, all right?
如果你用对套路
But just play your cards right,
也许你跟...也许玛榭会...
maybe you and, uh, maybe Marcella will, uh,
-也许她会跟你玩玩  -好吧
- maybe she'll play with you. - Okay.
会很挤的
Now, it's gonna be a tight squeeze.
谁想坐我腿上
Who wants to sit on my lap?
要跟着他吗
Want to go after him?
不用  我们可以通过这个找到他
No, we're gonna get to him through this guy.
就像当年一样是吧
Ah-ha! Just like the good old days, huh?
你搞笑吗
Are you kidding me?
这可比当年好多了
This is way better than the good old days.
我居然丢了一只鞋
I--I'm actually missing a shoe.
我们这是在哪里
Hey, where are we?
我觉得这是霍博肯酒店
Uh, I think we're in Hoboken.
你找我有事吗
You wanted to see me?
我让你别去见乔伊  你没听我的话吧
Did you go see Joy after I told you not to?
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我本来不知道  你刚告诉我的
I didn't. Until now.
我跟你说过了
I told you,
小狗狗没法清理自己的便便
a puppy can't clean up its own mess.
什么便便  我只不过给她讲了我奶奶的事
Mess? All I did was tell her about my grandmother.
你的任务是要给我减轻负担
Your job is to make my life easier.
如果这你都不明白  那我雇你干什么
If you can't understand that, why did I hire you?
这是报案记录的总结
Police report summarized.
交通信号分析
Traffic signal analysis.
出租车牌照的报价  出席者和竞拍结果
Medallion bids, attendees, and results.
你雇我就是干这些的
That's why you hired me.
我还以为你一心扑在乔伊的案子上了
I thought you were all over the Joy situation.
结果整个第六版都是关于你的报道
Instead, you're all over page six.
你不是想让我做无偿法律服务吗  这就是
You wanted me to do pro bono work, this is it.
无偿法律服务是为了提升律所的形象
Pro bono enhances a firm's image.
而这却让我们看起来像地主恶霸
This makes us look like wealthy bullies
欺负一个普通的出租车司机
against an everyman cabbie.
你觉得这有助于提高我们律所的形象吗
Does that seem like it enhances our image to you?
我拒绝回答这个问题
I refuse to answer that,
因为我不想回答
on the grounds that I don't want to.
有人昨晚玩得很爽啊
Someone had a fun night.
又接了一个不该接的电话吗
Answer another call you shouldn't have?
我没有...  我那是在...
I--I-- I didn't--I was--
给你个提示  领导向下级抛出的问题
Piece of advice-- when the big dog asks the puppy
有时只是反问而已
something like that, it's a rhetorical question.
明白了
Got it.
等等
Before you go,
那天开会时
the phone call, the other day,
你接的那个电话...
when you answered it during the meeting...
抱歉  我以后不会了
Yeah. Sorry about that. Won't happen again.
谁打来的
Who was it?
一个朋友而已  有点急事
Um, it's just a friend. You know, an emergency.
什么样的急事
What kind of emergency?
是不是那个让你走私毒品
Was it a friend who almost got you
害你差点被捕的朋友
busted for drug trafficking?
是他吗  特雷弗
That friend? Trevor?
他洗手不干了  哈维
He's not dealing anymore, harvey.
看来确实是他
So it was him.
他从监狱里打给你的吗
He called you from jail?
要知道  做律师这行
You know, I make a living
要学会读心  迈克
learning how to read people, Mike.
既然我能看穿你  那杰西卡也能
So if I saw it, Jessica did too.
这就是你想给大家留下的印象吗
Is that the kind of impression you want to leave around here?
那家伙不是你朋友
This guy is not your friend.
他只能拖你后腿  甩掉他吧
He is an anchor dragging you down. Get rid of him.
他是我交情最久的朋友  哈维
He is my oldest friend, Harvey.
我不能眼睁睁看着他在监狱里受罪
I wasn't just gonna let him rot in jail.
那下次你想怎么办
What's gonna happen the next time?
因为注定还会有下次
'Cause there will be a next time.
你还会保他出来吗
You gonna bail him out?
置你自己的安危于不顾吗
Put yourself in jeopardy?
要是没有特雷弗
You know, if it weren't for Trevor,
我们永远不可能认识
you and I never would've met.
甩掉他吧
Cut him loose.
我们想见迈克・罗斯
We're here to see Mike Ross.
他是个助理律师
He's an associate.
他的朋友特雷弗推荐我们来的
His friend Trevor referred us.
谢谢你
Thank you.
看样子他们可认识你  而且不是因为什么好事
It looked like they knew you, and not in a very good way.
警官  请问
Excuse me, officer.
中央公园是这么走吗
Is-- is Central Park that way?
对  就是沿着这条街走
Yeah, just go right there.
不好意思
Uh, I'm sorry, I'm--I'm--
我真是个十足的路痴
I'm really terrible with direction.
你是说沿着这条路走吗
Is it this street, right here?
-对  这条路  -这条路
- Yeah, this street, yes. - This street.
就在那里吗
Right here?
-对  -好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
特雷弗  我是迈克  给我回电
Trevor, it's Mike. Call me back.
告诉我到底发生了什么
I need to know what the hell's going on.
那些红天鹅绒纸杯蛋糕你拿了吗
Did you get the red velvet cupcakes?
拿了  三十六个  多加糖衣
Yes, three dozen, extra icing.
那是怎么弄的
How the hell did that happen?
既然这样
Okay. You know what?
好了  问题解决了
There. Problem solved.
我是问你  衣服是怎么弄破了
I asked you, how'd you get that tear?
有几个人去了咱们律所
A couple of guys came to the firm.
想要找我
They were looking for me.
我不知道他们找我干什么  但我...
I don't know what they wanted, but I'm...
我很清楚这和特雷弗做过的事有关
I'm pretty sure it something to do with some shit Trevor did.
你那聪明的小脑瓜
And that big brain of yours
不记得我让你和那个窝囊废断绝关系吗
doesn't remember me saying to cut ties with that loser?
你知道吗
You know what?
整整一周你都在忙你朋友的案子
You've been blowing off Joy's deal
完全顾不上乔伊  你有什么资格说我
all week for your friend, okay? So please.
首先  特雷弗不是你朋友
First of all, Trevor's not your friend.
你想知道我为什么会帮助雷吗
You want to know why I'm loyal to Ray?
那次我把三千美元落在了一辆豪华轿车里
I was taking a limo, and I left $3,000 in it.
司机恰巧就是雷
Ray happened to be the driver.
他捡到钱后  找到我
He found it and tracked me down.
分文不少地还给了我
Not a nickel of it was missing,
车祸发生后  他的第一反应是
And his first reaction when this accident occurred
问我们受没受伤
was to ask if we were okay.
如果换做特雷弗  他会怎样
Now, what would Trevor's have been?
甩掉他吧
Cut him off.
既然说到了授权合约这个案子
Now, as far as the licensing deal goes,
虽然你认为我无暇顾及
just because you think I'm blowing something off
但事实并非如此
doesn't mean I am.
瞧我的  学着点
Now, watch and learn.
你离任的前期工作都安排妥当了
Everything's set for you to walk away.
我们将整体抛售你所持有的股份
We're selling your stake as a block.
目前猎头正在物色你的下任
Your, uh, headhunter's lining up your replacement as we speak.
哈维
Well, Harvey,
这简直太让我惊喜了
this was the most wonderful surprise.
你是我们的长期客户  你又那么想和家人团聚
You're a long-time client who wants to be with her family.
这是我应该做的
It's the least I could do.
你马上就能拥有大把的时光和孩子们
And you'll have all the free time in the world
-共享天伦  -乔伊把微波炉打破了
- to spend with them. - Joey broke the microwave.
太棒了
Oh, that's great.
要多久才能把他们送回家
Now, how soon can we send 'em home?
他们订的是明早最早的航班
They're booked on the first flight out, tomorrow morning.
你让唐娜把孩子们的名字发给你...
So when you had Donna text you the girls' names--
我指的是她亲生女儿们的名字
I was talking about her daughters.
于是你就把她们都接来了
And you were gonna fly them out all along.
你记不记得我说过
Do you remember when I said,
"没人会让小狗狗清理自己的便便"
"You don't send a puppy to clean up its own mess?"
我记得  哈维
Yes, Harvey, I do.
我可不是小狗狗
I'm not a puppy.
开庭
Court will come to order.
桑塔纳先生  请做开庭陈述
Mr. Santana, your opening statement, please.
出租车司机是个平凡的职业
Driving a cab is not very glamorous.
但也是份勤恳务实的工作
But it's an honest day's work.
自从入行以来
Ever since I started,
我就希望能够告诉乘客
I looked forward to a time when I could tell customers
他们乘坐的是我的车子
that they were riding in my cab.
我是一个自主营业者
That I was an owner-operator.
所以我精打细算  勤俭节约
So I scrimped, and I saved,
终于攒够钱可以买执照了
until I finally had enough put away to buy a medallion.
但是...
But...
因为这位男士的行为
Because of the actions of this man,
我失去了这个机会
I've lost that opportunity.
毫无疑问
So make no mistake, this--
这场审讯的重点并非破碎的前照灯
This trial is not about a busted headlight.
而是破碎的梦想
This is a trial about a broken dream.
瞧他那架势  和总统竞职演说似的
Forget the case, they're gonna make him president.
开庭陈述就像罚球  简单得很
Statements are like free throws--easy.
因为没人防守
Nobody's playing defense.
我们善于防守吗
Are we good at defense?
你同意私人司机会引发更多的事故吗
You would agree that chauffeur drivers cause more accidents--
反对  骚扰证人
Objection. Badgering.
反对有效
Sustained.
反对  问题具有争论性
Objection. Argumentative.
引导证人
Leading the witness.
问题不明确
Ambiguous.
免责条款
Privileged.
-言论具有煽动性  -反对有效
- Inflammatory. - Sustained.
还有问题吗  桑塔纳先生
Anything further, Mr. Santana?
有  法官大人
Yes, your honor,
我想传召迈克尔・罗斯先生作证
I would like to call to the stand Mr. Michael Ross, please.
在发生事故的那天
What time had you called for the limo
你什么时候叫了豪华轿车
on the morning of the accident?
我们应该是八点半离开的
Uh, we were supposed to leave at 8:30.
那你几点上班
And what time did you get to work?
反对  与本案无关
Objection. Irrelevant.
关系重大  法官大人
It's highly relevant, your honor.
这与司机拉希姆・班加西当时的心理状况有关
It speaks to the psychology of the driver, rahim Benghazi.
反对无效
Overruled.
回答桑塔纳先生的问题
Answer Mr. Santana's question.
八点四十
8:40.
所以说  除非班加西先生在十分钟内赶到
So unless Mr. Benghazi made up for that lost time,
你面谈就会迟到  对吧
you were going to be late for that meeting, correct?
是的
Yes.
讯问完毕  法官大人
No further questions, your honor.
事故发生的时候
When the accident occurred,
你在去执照拍卖会的路上
you were on your way to the medallion auction.
这个拍卖会是在何时何地举行的
When and where was this auction to take place?
早上九点  在市政府
9:00 A.M., city hall.
根据警方的报告
According to the police report,
事故发生在上午8:53
the accident occurred 8:53 a.m.
也就意味着你只有七分钟时间
That means you only had seven minutes
在高峰期开往市中心
to get downtown in rush hour traffic.
反对  与本案无关
Objection, irrelevant.
在我提出同样的反对时
I believe when I made the same objection,
你告诉法官大人"关系重大"
you told his honor it was highly relevant.
反对无效
Overruled.
你也快要迟到了
You were running late,
只不过你迟到的后果比我们更为严重
only the stakes for you were much higher, weren't they?
拍卖会从未准时开始过
These things never start on time.
那为什么在9:03时
Then why was the first medallion
售出了第一个执照
sold 9:03 a.m.?
你担心你拍到执照的机会化为泡影
You were scared your chance at a medallion was going up in smoke,
所以你闯了红灯
and you ran a red.
然后利用事故
Then you used the accident
让我和雷・班加西做替罪羊
to paint me and Ray Benghazi as a couple of scapegoats.
你不能证明这一点
You can't prove that.
当时交通灯是什么颜色
What color was the light?
我引用第五修正案[不得要求自证其罪]
I take the fifth.
你不引用第五修正案  桑塔纳先生
You can't take the fifth, Mr. Santana.
这不是刑事调查
This isn't a criminal case.
灯是什么颜色的
What color was the light?
他插到了我前面
He cut me off.
你声称非常拥护我们的法律系统
You claim to love our legal system so much,
请回答问题
answer the question.
灯是什么颜色的
What color was the light?
法官大人
Your honor?
回答这个问题  桑塔纳先生
Answer the question, Mr. Santana.
那对我意义重大
It just meant so much to me.
法官大人
Your honor,
我能和对方律师商量一下吗
can I sidebar with opposing counsel?
我们可以把胜负交给陪审团来判定
We can roll the dice with the jury,
但我更希望进行和解
but I'd rather settle.
好吧  我要赔多少钱
Well, how much would I have to pay?
无需赔偿
Nothing.
你来承担事故的责任
You take responsibility for the accident,
雷的全部损失将由保险公司承担
and your insurance company makes Ray whole.
作为回报
In return,
我放弃索要诉讼费的权利
I waive my right to collect legal fees.
我不知道说什么
I don't know what to say.
什么也别说了
Don't say anything.
我得维护自己的名誉
I've got a reputation to maintain.
法官大人  为了您的名誉  请公正裁决
That goes for you too, judge.
真该死  特雷弗  我给你留了五条留言
Damn it, Trevor. I left you like five messages.
你兄弟跟谁都只是玩玩  真好
Good to know your boy's flaky with everyone.
我是来寻私仇的
I was taking it personal.
你想要什么
What do you want?
特雷弗欠我的五万块钱没还
Well, Trevor owes us $50,000 he's never paid,
你得拿钱来赎他
so you're gonna bail him out.
听着  我没那么多钱给你
Listen, I don't have that kind of money, okay? I can't.
如果你一小时内不带着钱过来
Well, if you're not down here in an hour with it,
我们就要特雷弗好看
we're gonna take it out on Trevor.
告诉他钱在哪里
Tell him where the money is.
千万不要露面
Whatever you do, don't show up.
特雷弗
Trevor!
你有一个小时的时间
You have one hour.
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
你在庭审中途离席
What do you think you're doing,
你觉得那么做合适吗
leaving in the middle of a trial?
我有事要去处理
I got some things to take care of.
你是说有人需要你帮忙吧
You mean someone to take care of.
你从没和特雷弗断绝联系  对吧
You never cut Trevor off, did you?
是啊  没断  我的朋友遇上麻烦了
No, I didn't. My friend's in trouble,
我要去帮他
and I'm gonna help him.
你知道吗  瘾君子都是这副德行
You know what? This is what addicts do.
每当事情有点起色  他们就会出岔子
The second they start making progress, they screw up,
因为在惨败之前
because deep down they think
他们深信  成功只是早晚的问题
it's only a matter of time until they fail.
他们宁愿从半山腰掉下来  也不会坚持到山顶
They'd rather fall from the third floor than the penthouse.
你说什么也不能阻止我
Nothing you say can stop me.
那么你就告诉我到底发生了什么事
Then tell me what the hell's going on.
身上没装窃听器
He's clean. No wires.
确定吗
Are you sure?
当然  我很确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
上次那个男人  你就没查出来
You remember what happened with the guy.
他可有三百磅重啊
He was 300 pounds.
你到底是什么身份
Now, who'd you say you were again?
特雷弗的律师
Trevor's lawyer.
特雷弗根本没提到他还有个律师
Trevor didn't mention a lawyer.
他不知道自己雇了我
He doesn't know he hired me.
过来
Come on.
把公文包打开
Open the briefcase.
尼玛我要的钱呢
Where's the goddamn money?
这张照片是我公司的安全录像机抓拍的
That photo is a screen shot, taken from my firm's security video.
我们知道了你们的长相
We know what you look like.
如果迈克・罗斯在接下来五分钟里
And if Mike Ross doesn't hear from me
没有收到我的消息  他就会报警了
in the next five minutes, he's calling the police.
不  小子  你过来可不是为了威胁我们的
No, man. You're not comin' in here and threatenin' us.
你被指控犯有绑架罪  敲诈罪和贩毒罪
You're looking at kidnapping, extortion, and drug-dealing,
而我的快速拨号键三
and the district attorney
就能联系到地区检察官
happens to be number three on my speed dial.
既然我们要蹲那么很久的监狱
Well, if we're looking at all that time,
你就再加上一项谋杀罪
you might as well add murder.
我有个更好的主意
I got a better idea.
这是律师聘用合同
Retainer agreement.
你在这把字一签
If you sign right here,
你就是我的客户了
you'll become one of my clients.
到时候即使我想告你
And I won't be able to testify against you,
法律也不允许
even if I wanted to.
钱的问题怎么解决
What about the money?
这个信封里有一万
This envelope contains $10,000.
你就当做是特雷弗欠款的首付金吧
Consider it a down payment on Trevor's debt.
但我要说明一件事
Only here's the thing,
我可从不做无偿的事
I don't do pro bono work.
我的律师聘用合同
And my retainer agreement
正好要求付一万的首付金
requires a down payment of $10,000.
现在  作为你的律师  我的工作是给你提建议
Now, as your attorney, my job is to give you advice.
我的建议就是
So here's the deal.
签了协议
Sign the agreement.
我不是要你别来嘛
I thought I said not to come.
你还记得五年级时欠我的40块吗
Remember that 40 bucks from the fifth grade you owe me?
你要是死了  我找谁要去
If you were dead, how would I collect?
老天
oh, man.
我真抱歉  只是...
I'm sorry, I just...
跟我在一起  你总是麻烦不断
Put you in trouble just by hanging out with you.
那你为什么要这样
So why'd you do it?
因为我是个混蛋
'cause I'm a dick.
你肯定没想到  你把我保释出来没多久
Bet you didn't think you'd have to save my ass
又要救我的命
so soon after bailing me out.
不是我救了你的命
I wasn't the one who saved you.
对  作为你的朋友
Yeah. Well, as a friend,
那家伙还真让我羞愧
the guy puts me to shame.
相信我  哈维不是我朋友
Harvey's not my friend, trust me.
谁信你  他可不是为了我而两肋插刀的
Well, he didn't put his ass on the line because of me.
听着  我已争取将你的罪罚降到了最低
Listen, I pled you down to a misdemeanor--
酗酒和妨害治安罪  我也帮你付了罚金
Drunk and disorderly. And I paid the fine.
我觉得你最好还是
I think it might be a good idea
出城去躲躲吧
if you got out of town for a while.
蒙大拿[美国州名]
Montana.
你不是说想痛改前非嘛
Well, you said you wanted a clean slate.
我觉得你在巴士上呆上20小时就差不多了
I figured 20 hours on a bus ought to do the trick.
那是那是  确实管用
Oh, yeah, it'll do me good.
我回来后
When I get back,
第一个电话会打给谁  你懂的
You know who the first person I'm gonna call is.
对  谁会接电话  你也懂的
Yeah. The one person you know who'll answer.
给你的
For you.
这是什么
What's this?
真高兴你终于无偿受理案件了
I'm very happy you took ray on pro bono.
这样你反而能为我们的服务买单了
You, on the other hand, can afford our services.
你这是要我自己
You want me
花钱雇我自己去为我自己打官司吗
to pay me to represent me?
对呀  一小时一千  总共十小时
Mm-hmm. Ten hours at $1,000 an hour.
还是你自己算算吧
Eh, yeah, I'll let you do the math.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
那我告诉你我对什么是认真的
I'll tell you what I am serious about.
我听说你终于开始教那孩子本事了
I hear you're finally mentoring the kid.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
真的吗  你不懂  我懂
Really, because I understand
你把那个小狗的比喻用到他身上了
that you dropped the puppy analogy on him,
就像当初我对你一样
which is exactly what I used on you.
大概是不经意间说出口的
May have slipped out by accident.
经意不经意并不重要
Well, accident, on purpose,
真正重要的事是
The really important thing is,
我比你高[职位也是]
is that I'm taller than you.
记得要乖
Yeah.
不错  你穿那件更显瘦
Yup, you look much thinner in that.
那事是你嫁祸给我的  是男人就承认
You planted that story, be man enough to own it.
哈维  我可买不通那些小报记者
I don't traffic in the tabloids, Harvey.
但我知道不论是谁嫁祸给你的
But I can see how whoever planted this
肯定觉得很可笑
might find it amusing.
你看  我们伟大的哈维斗士
You know, the great Harvey specter
竟然欺负一个老实的出租车司机
bullying a humble cab driver.
此案必败
I mean, it's a no-win situation, really.
看来你还没听说
Well, maybe you didn't hear.
我赢了这场必败之战
I won the no-win situation.
你难道不懂   如果你没有暗算我
Did it ever occur to you that if you hadn't done that to me,
我会觉得自己欠你的人情
I actually would have owed you one?
如果你没在同事面前羞辱我的话...
Maybe if you didn't humiliate me in front of the associates--
路易  对于一位普通的律师而言
Louis, for an average attorney,
打赢一亿的官司是毕生梦想
100 million is a career case.
如果我耻笑了你
If I'm mocking you,
那说明我认为你高于一般水准
it means I think you're above average.
不过玩减压球  你玩得太简单了
But stress balls? You're making it too easy.
你把特雷弗送上驶向荒野的大巴了
You put Trevor on the bus to the boondocks?
对  我能问你个问题吗
Yeah. Can I ask you a question?
这件事之后  你觉得我还会相信
After all this, you really think I'm still buying
你是个"事不关己  高高挂起"的人吗
the Mr. I-don't-give-a-crap thing?
乔伊送给你一个小纪念品表达感激
Joy sent a little token of her appreciation.
她把你的发型做得恰到好处
She got your hair just right.
她也给你做过这样的娃娃吗
Did she ever make one of these for you?
我不会给你看的
Not that you'll ever see.